Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal Papers, Series 6.
  - Subseries 3. Documents, address books, and miscellaneous material
    - Miscellaneous Legal-size Material, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Calendar with pictures of Stalin, Lenin, Trotsky, Zhukov. Print of two bottles of Georgian mineral water [?]. The Daily Telegraph, "Cheltenham Festival of Literature 1995," folder, 1995. Legal-size manila folder with prices and notes, n.d.
    - I.D. cards, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Vsesoiuznoe soveshchanie molodykh pisatelei, 1951 Mar. Conferencia mundial de solidaridad por Chile (World Conference of Solidarity for Chile), 1978 Nov. 12. Gorodskoi internatisional'nyi esperanto-club, 1982 Feb. 13. Sovetskii komitet zashchity mira, 1989 Dec. 31. Sovetskii sport (press pass), 1989 Dec. 31. University of Pennsylvania, 1991 May 30. S'ezd Rossiskikh Pisatelei, 1991 Oct. 21. ITIC, International Teacher/Professor Identity Card, 1993 Apr. 21. Komapaniia "Rosugol'", 1996 May 30. Soiuz Pisatelei SSSR, n.d. Pacificare of Oklahoma, n.d.
    - Publishing Agreements, 1951 - 1979 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Sovetskii Kompozitor; Rusconi Libri; Molodaia Gvardiia; Sovetskii Pisatel'
    - Publishing Agreements, 1980 - 1997 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Newton Compton editori s.r.l.; Liberty Publishing House, Inc.; Izdatelstvo "Eksmo"; Znanie; Distribuidora Record de Servicos de Imprensa S.A.; Zaural'e; Briarwood Writers' Alliance, Inc.; Secker & Warburg; Ruggles de Latour, Inc.; Reed International Books Australia Pty Ltd; Podriadchika
    - Financial Documents (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Europaverlag; Marion Boyars Publishers Ltd.; Village Gate; VAAP-INFO
    - Bank account (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Aktsionernyi Kommercheskii Bank "Chara"; information for Lloyd's Bank.
    - Property documentation: Peredelkino, ul. Gogolia, 1 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, resolutions, repairs estimates, rent forms, certificates.
    - Insurance certificates, 1988 - 1989 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Medical, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Ownership documents for paintings, 1977 - 1986 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Handwritten letter from Iosif Noneshvich, signed,1 p., 1977 Dec. 14. Spravka, copy of typescript, signed by Milan Iovanovich, 1 p., 1978 Apr. 12. Typescript, 1 p., signed by Nikita Bogoslovskii, 1978 July 2. Handwritten note from M.F. Nikonova, signed, 1 p., 1978 July 17. Spravka, typescript, signed by B. Filippov, 1978 July 12. Typescript, signed by Bella Akhmadulina, 1 p., 1978 July 12. Typescript, signed by V. Sheskin, 1 p., 1978 Aug. 12. Typescript, signed by R.F. Kazakova, 1 p., 1978 Aug. 12. Spravka, typescript, signed by Milan Iovanovich, 1978 July 12. Raspiska, typescript, signed by G.S. Yevtushenko, 1979 Nov. 1. Typescript, signed by Tselkov, n.d. Handwritten note, signed by G. Yevtushenko, 1986 May 23
      Akhmadulina, Bella; Tselkov, N.; Yevtushenko, G.; Filippov, B.; Bogoslovskii, Nikita V.; Iovanovich, Milan; Kazakova, R.; Nikonova, M.F.; Noneshvich, I.; Sheskin, V.
    - A. Watkins note giving Mark Twain's cane to Yevtushenko, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 8.1)
      Copy of handwritten note, 1 p.
      Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Watkins, A.
    - Whale bone certification, 1973 Dec. 19 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Typescript signed by William Magee, Department of Economic Development, Government of Northwest Territories, Canada, 1 p., 1973 Dec. 19; Material listing and invoice, 2 p., 1973 Dec. 19
    - Passport, 1992 - 1997 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Travel and visa documents, 1993 - 1994 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      Correspondence; copies of resident alien cards and passports for Maria, Yevgeny, and Dmitri Yevtushenko; USIA certificate of eligibility for J-1 visa status.
      University of Tulsa
    - Immigration Materials (Box 41, Folder 12)
      Petition approval from the INS for alien worker. Copies of passports. Marriage certificate. J-1 application. Application for Employment Authorization. Biographic information forms. Chase Manhattan Bank letter. University of Tulsa appointment letter. Letter from Consulate General of Russian Federation expressing no objections to green cards for Yevtushenko and his family. Letter from Russian PEN center confirming end of marriage between Yevtushenko and Akhmadulina.
      Novikova, Ganna Nikolaevna; Yevtushenko, Maria
    - Itineraries, undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Travel receipts, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Business Cards, undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Pages from Address Books, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Calendar, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Address Books [1 of 6], undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Address Books [2 of 6], undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Address Books [3 of 6], undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Address Books [4 of 6], undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Address Books [5 of 6], undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Address Books [6 of 6], undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Address Books: International [1 of 4], undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Address Books: International [2 of 4], undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Address Books: International [3 of 4], undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Address Books: International [4 of 4], undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Artistic representations of Yevtushenko, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Sketches, drawings, pictures of paintings, etc. Signed sketch by Kurt Vonnegut, [copy?] 1996 Mar. 17.
      Vonnegut, Kurt
    - Narodnye Deputaty SSSR and Verkhovnyi Sovet SSSR, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Binder with listing of all members.
    - Autoportrait on the Sharp Edge of the Kremlin Tower..., undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Multiple copies of cardboard poster [?].
    - Portraits of Lüfti Özkök, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Photocopied brochure of his work, photograph, postcard with picture of Nazim Hikmet.
    - Letterhead: Tvorcheskoe obieedenie 'Slovo', undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Program signed by USSR olympic soccer team, 1986 Apr. 16 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Maps, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
      Greece, Israel, Tbilisi, Western-Central United States, Copacabana, Moscow
    - Picture: "L'espace et le temps sont a tour": Paul Edward, 1981 Jan. 2 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Picture composed of magazine cut-outs, with signatures on the back.
      Skabard, T.; Edward, Paul
    - Neck Owner's Manual, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Brochure.
    - Excerpt from Encyclopedia, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Copy from book. Copy of front pages with inscription by Yevtushenko to EDE, 1972.
    - Chto mozhno lechit' pixtovym maslom, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Student Final Papers: Queens College, Russian 250, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Course Posters, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Results of Student Survey in Oklahoma, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Student Reviews of "Stalin's Funeral": 1997 Sept. (Box 43, Folder 13.1)
    - Course Materials (Box 43, Folder 13.2)
      Notes by to Peter Carravetta from Vladimir Lunis concerning a focus group of heritage Russian speakers, typescript, 3 p., 1997 Feb. 14; handwritten course description, 1 p., n.d.; syllabus for course "Russian/European Cinema", Fall 1998, typescript, 3 p.; handwritten response to questions for Russian Cinema course; computer-generated list of students and grades, spring 1993; cover "Kliuch k Russkoi dusha"; listing of professors, 2 p.
    - Flyers for public demonstrations (Box 43, Folder 14)
      Copies.
    - Printed Material: Friends (Box 43, Folder 15)
      Brochures and flyers.
      Nunn, Ancel E.; Likhachev, D.; Shevardnadze, Eduard; Okudzhava, Bulat; Chichibabin, Boris; Vasil'ev, Iu.; Chemiakin, M.; Tselkov, Oleg; Kazanov; Williams, Penny; Gerinas, Aleksandr; Vrubel, Dmitrij
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 43, Folder 16)
      Brochures, flyers, and cards.
    - Book Jacket for John Updike book in Russian translation: "Krolik begi" and "Davai pozhenimsia" (Box 43, Folder 17)
      Updike, John
    - Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Conference Name tags, undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
      Issyk-kol Forum, Kyrgyzstan 1997. My Brother's Keeper, World Jewish Congress, n.d. Cinema Art Festival, n.d. Eleventh Cowboy Poetry Gathering, Moscow, Russia, n.d.
    - Znachki [pins], undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
      International Peace to the Oceans Committee. Shakhterskaia Slava
    - Sound reel: Avtorskii vecher Yevtushenko:, Nov. 17; Sound reel. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      (zapis' iz Kolonnogo - zala Doma Soiuzov ot 17 noiabria)
    - Audiotapes: "Ia raznyi", 1999; Audiotapes. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      "chitaet avtor, poet Iurii Aitzhanov"; two copies.
    - CD: Roskosh' Bednykh, 1999; CD (Box 44, Folder 3)
      golos poeta; two copies.
    - CD: Pesni na stikhi Y. Yevtushenko poiut T. i S. Nikitiny, 1999; CD (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Filmstrip: Unidentified, undated; filmstrip (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Yevtushenko and [?] outside with bridge in background
    - CD: The City of Yes, The City of No (Box 44, Folder 44.1)
    - The Oklahoma Summer Arts Institute 1996 Schedule (Box 44, Folder 44.2)
    - Miscellaneous Oversized, undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Festa Nazionale Dell' Unita', Roma, 1984; flyer for exhibit "Shadows and Faces," bookjacket for "Ia sibirskoi porody," Placard to Yevtushenko from the Soviet Collective in Argentina, 1984 April 22; black and white sketch of Yevtushenko by Rafael Pisarev'; broadside of Soviet leaders of the Brezhnev era standing at attention at the Lenin Mausoleum, entitled "The Pepsi Generation," poster for "Itogi Veka: Vzgliad iz Rossii;" "History Transposed: a Teaching Map: A reflection, on my first trip to the Soviet Union: how would it feel to be a Russian, and to have grown up in their reality?" by Paul Winter, 1984 July.
      Pisarev, Rafael; Winter, Paul
    - Chislennost' naseleniia Rossii, 1894 - 1987; graph (Box 81, Folder 1)
      Graph showing population growth (and decline) in Russia, 1 p.
    - Record: "16 songs of young poets", undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
      Rozhdestvenskii, Robert; Okudzhava, Bulat
    - Address Book, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Address Book: International [1 of 2], 1991 -1992; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Address Book: International [2 of 2], 1994; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Anti-Yevtushenko Propaganda, 1972; Accession 2004-022; Brochures, flyers (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Course Materials, 1996 - 2002; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Invitation to Yevtushenko's Russian Dinner, 2000 Nov. 4; Accession 2004-022; Postcard with insert (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Postcards to Yevtushenko, 1996 - 2002; includes undated materials; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Student's Works, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Advertisement Drawing, undated; Accession 2004-022; Oversized drawing (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Advertisement Poster, undated; Accession 2004-022; Oversized poster (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 7, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 8, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 9, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 10, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 11, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 12, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Course Materials "The Key to the Russian Soul", Book 2, chpt. 12, 1993; Accession 2004-022 (Box 107, Folder 6)
- Photographs, Series 7.
  This series consists of thousands of photographs of Yevtushenko's private and public life in addition to some slides, negatives, and film clips.
  - Subseries 1. General
    - 1940 - 1949, photographs (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Peredacha Semen Koshko na radio, 1941 Jan 21. Yevtushenko with friends, 1949
    - Photographs, 1940 - 1949; photographs (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, 1950 - 1959; photographs (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Yevtushenko in Sukhumi, 1952. Yevtushenko and Italian writer Vittorio Strada, 1957
      Strada, Vittorio
    - Photographs, 1960 - 1965; photographs (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Yevtushenko in Khar'kov, 1960; First visit to Babii Iar, Kiev, with I. Kazimirov, 1961; In Abkhaziia with I. Gutchin and others, 1963; In Stantsiia Zima, 1963; Paris, 1963 Feb.; Photo of Life magazine cover, 1963 May 6; Crimea, Massandra, 1965 July 30; With Georgian poet Geno Kalonda [?]; Bratskaia GES, 1965; In Armenia, 1965, with Gevorg Emin; On "Mikeshkin" with photo correspondent E. Briukhanenko [?], 1965
      Gutchin, I.; Gogua, A.; Kalonda, Geno; Kalandin, G.; Padilla, Heberto; Kazimirov, I.; Emin, Gevorg; Burkovy, B.
    - Na Krasnoiarskikh stolbakh, 1964; photographs (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1966; photographs (Box 44, Folder 10)
      Tbilisi; Siberia; John and Mary Updike; at the grave of Svetlov with Ia. Smeliakov; Mikeshkin.
      Smeliakov, Ia.; Updike, John; Svetlov
    - Photographs, 1967 - 1969; photographs (Box 44, Folder 11)
      At the dacha of Karlo Kaladze with poet Charkviani and sculptor G. Kaladze [?]; in Melbourne, 1967; Yugoslavia, 1967; photo inscribed to Yevtushenko and signed by Volodia Dolgin, Mexico, 1968 Mar. 18.
      Charkviani, D.; Dolgin, Volodia
    - Photographs, 1970; photographs (Box 44, Folder 12)
      Angarsk, 1970; Minsk with Andrei Makayonok [?], playwright and editor-in-chief of "Neman" magazine.
      Makayonok, A.
    - Kazan', 1970; photographs (Box 44, Folder 13)
      With M. Valeev - ideological secretary of the Communist Party of Tatarstan (helped Yevtushenko with the poem "Kazan's University"; at newspaper "Komsomolets Tatartstana".
    - Photographs, 1971 - 1972; photographs (Box 45, Folder 1)
      In Angarsk; In Vladivostok with writers of "Novyi Mir"; with journalist LG [?] V. Pomazkov [?]; Allison Krause, with note from Doris and Arthur Krause, 1972 Jan. 31.
      Krause, Allison
    - Photographs, 1973; photographs (Box 45, Folder 2)
      With O. Tselkov, Gosha Balakshin [?], Shinkarev [?] and Valery Chernikh [?] on the Vilni [?] River; Frankie [Avelino?]; in Iakutsk; Stantsiia Zima.
      Balakshin, G.; Chernikh, V.; Efimov; Shinkarev; Tselkov, Oleg
    - Photographs, 1974; photographs (Box 45, Folder 3)
      In Koktebel; with Sergei Orlov, Oleg Mikhailov; in Vladivostok; In Armenia with M. Golovastchkov [?]; in Izmailov with A.M. Inkov.
      Mikhailov, Oleg; Orlov, Sergei; Inkov, A.
    - Photographs, 1975; photographs (Box 45, Folder 4)
      In Armenia; on the Aldan river in Siberia; at a gypsy wedding in Sverdlovsk; BAM; in Bratskaia GES; Kazakhstan with Mukhtar Shakhanov.
    - Photographs, 1976; photographs (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Kulikovo pole; Lipezkaya; Leningrad; Tblisi; with Moldovan poet Petr Zadnipru; in Sukhumi, with Jan Butler
      Charkviani, D.; Zadnipru, Petr
    - Magnitogorsk and Cheliabinsk, 1976; photographs (Box 45, Folder 6)
      With son Petia in Magnitogorsk.
    - Photographs, 1977 - 1979; photographs (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Alma-Ata; with Mukhtar Shakhanov, Kazakh poet; with wife Jan Butler; Vilnius opening of Yevtushenko's photo exhibit; with Albert Todd in Vilnius; in Georgia; International Film Festival in Moscow 1979.
      Shakhanov, Mukhtar
    - Photographs, 1980; photographs (Box 45, Folder 8)
      At the grave of Pasternak 20 years after his death; with N. Chikirev, director of the Moscow Instrument Factory; in Ulan-Ude, Buryat Autonomous Republic.
      Chikirev, N.
    - Pokhoroni Vysotskogo [Vysotsky's Funeral], 1980; photographs (Box 45, Folder 9)
      Photo from funeral; calendars.
      Vysotsky, Vladimir
    - Photographs, 1981 - 1985; photographs (Box 45, Folder 10)
      With William Jay Smith, American poet, 1981; with Ingeborg teek Frank and Albert Todd in New York, 1982 Apr. 29; with Eduard Treskin, Kazan opera singer, 1982; with poet M. Nikulina; Chingiz Aitmatov, Kyrgyz writer; house in Gulripshi; "The 2nd Global Town Meeting", 1984 Dec. 9; with Kazakh poet Olzhas Suleimenov; Nikolai Rubtsov.
      Frank, Ingebork teek; Carlovna, Maria; Aitmatov, Chingiz; Treskin, Eduard; Todd, Albert; Suleimenov, Olzhas; Smith, William Jay; Rubtsov, Nikolai
    - Opening of photo exhibit at Mayakovsky Museum: Moscow, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      Mayakovsky Museum
    - Photographs, 1986 - 1987; photographs (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Photographs, 1988 - 1989; photographs (Box 45, Folder 13)
      Photo exhibit "Divided Twins" with Boyd Norton; deputies from Ukraine; with Karelian poet Marat Tarasov, 1989.
      Okudzhava, Bulat; Norton, Boyd
    - Khar'kov, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Photographs, 1990 - 1992; photographs (Box 46, Folder 1)
      In Siberia (Stantsia Zima) with Dzhumber Betashvili, the Bouis family, and Albert Todd, 1991. Dissolution [?] of the Writer's Union, with V. Ognev and G. Pulatov [?], 1991.
      Klein, Jenny; Ognev, V.; Betashvili, Dzhumber; Bouis, Nina; Todd, Albert; Riks, Helga
    - Photographs, 1993 - 1995; photographs (Box 46, Folder 2)
      At the "Trud" editorial office; in St. Petersburg with Sobchak; with film director Georgii Daneliia, 1993; with Roberto Assardo, University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point; Commmencent at University of Tulsa, 1993 May 8; Briansk, 1994; with American poet Kim Stafford at Cowboy's Festival in Elko, Colorado, 1994
      Sobchak, A.; Stafford, Kim; Assardo, Roberto; Daneliia, G.
    - Photographs, 1996 - 1997; photographs (Box 46, Folder 3)
      In the city of Kungur, 1996; with XGS - Moscow Publishing house after presentation of the book "Samoe - Samoe" in Biblio-Gladus; in Ivanovo at the dacha of the editor of the local paper, V. Sokolov, 1997; With Natal'ia, Lazar', and Nadia [?] Shafer in Pavlodar, 1997; Madrid, 1997.
      Shafer; Sokolov, V.; McVay, Gordon
    - Photographs, 1998; photographs (Box 46, Folder 4)
      With Georgian writers Dzhansug [?] Charkviani and Shota Nishnianidze; with sons Zhenia and Mitia in Samara; Chicago - opening of Yevtushenko museum with Mark Levin; Chicago - evening in memory of B. Okudzhava; with Albert Todd and wife Masha in New York; Yevtushenko's class "Yevtushenko on Yevtushenko", "Russian Samovar" in New York.
      Todd, Albert; Levin, Mark; Nishnianidze, S.; Charkviani, D.
    - Brighton Beach:, 1999 May; photographs (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Reading organized by "Medical Consultant" magazine, 1999 May.
    - Photographs, 1999; photographs (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Almaty; with Il'ia Rudiakov [?], owner of a Russian bookstore in Chicago; with pictures is a note from Phyllis Putler Barasch; Tyler Museum of Art in Tyler, TX, pictures signed by Ancel E. Nunn.
      Levin, Mark; Barasch, Marvin; Shakhanov, Mukhtar; Nunn, Ancel E.
    - Vruchenie Yevtushenko premii Uolta Uotmana [presentation of Walt Whitman prize]:, 1999 July 4; photographs (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Queen's College with Albert Todd, 1999; photographs (Box 46, Folder 8)
      Todd, Albert
    - People: A - H, undated; photographs (Box 46, Folder 9)
      First abstract exhibition in Ismailovo Park, Moscow; banquet after premiere of "Vzlet", TsDL; In Tbilisi with Georgian writiers Charkviani and Nodar Dumbadze; at the Writer's Union in Moscow; with sculptor Kochar and poet Gevorg Emin[?]; with Marina Tsvetaeva's translator Helen Feinstein in England; with Croatian artist Ivan Generalic; with Armand Hammer in his office, also with former California governor Jerry Brown, and Albert Todd.
      Generalic, Ivan; García Márquez, Gabriel; Hammer, Armand; Gogua, A.; Kochar, E.; Bondarchuk, S. F.; Shergova, G.; Rosi, Francesco; Todd, Albert; Tarba, Ivan; Anikina, Natalia; Aliger, Margarita; Akhmadulina, Bella; Artemov, Volodia; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1960; Azhaev, V.; Baruzdin, Sergei; Baryshnikov, M.; Borevu, Iu.; Briukhenenko, E.; Voznesenskīĭ, Andreĭ; Brown, Jerry; Butita, I.; Cela, Camilo Jose; Charkviani, D.; Delone, Vadim; Dumbadze, Nodar; Emin, Gevorg; Feinstein, Helene; Francois, Jean-Philippe
    - People: I - R, undated; photographs (Box 46, Folder 10)
      With Iu. Kariakin, specialist on Dostoevksy; with Indian poet Evg. Khaisa [?]; with Azerbaijanian poet Nabi Khazri; with the editor of "Sovetskaya Sporta"; working on anthology with journalist Feliks Medvedev.
      Lesnevskii, S.; Kurbanov, T.; Kolmanovskii, E.; Khazri, Nabi; Miro, Joan; Medvedev, Feliks; Makarov, A.; Levin, Mark; Nikulina, M.; Neizvestnyi, Nekio; Naumov, V.; Murmazaev, Sh.; Abashidze, I.; Kariakin, Iu.; Roshin, Michael
    - People: S, undated; photographs (Box 46, Folder 11)
      Shul'zhenko, K.; Smith, William Jay; Shinkarev, Leonid; Shitov, A.; Shakhanov, Mukhtar; Shestalovi, Iu.; Stevenson, Time; Stone, Jeremy
    - People: T - Z, undated; photographs (Box 46, Folder 12)
      Vikhliantsevu, Iu.; Vysotsky, Vladimir; West, Morris; Zhdanov, V.
    - Places: Belarus - Kiev, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Belarus; Georgia; Iakutiia; Kamchatka; Kazakhstan; Kazan'; Kiev.
    - Places: Kurchatovskii institute - Moldova, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Kurchatovskii institute; Latvia; Lipezk; Moldova.
    - Places: Peredelkino, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Pasternak's grave; guests from Israel.
    - Places: Mongolia - Volgograd, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Mongolia; at museum of Pavel Vasiliev in Pavlodar; Samara; Stantsiia Zima; Sverdlovsk; Vladivostok; Volgograd.
    - Miscellaneous [1 of 2], undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 5)
      "My American Students"; meeting with the magazine "Znamia"; Funeral of Uncle Andrei.
    - Miscellaneous [2 of 2], undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Group from "Poet in Russia is more than a poet;" Kulikove pole; TsDL.
    - Slides and Positives, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - General Negatives, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Photos of Yevtushenko taken by V. Serova, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Proofs, undated; photographs (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Russia, 2000 Jul. 29 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - USA, 1998 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Portrait, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Portrait [?], n. d., undated (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of portrait, n. d., undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Yevtushenko with his son Sasha, 1997 Oct. 12 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Yevtushenko with Peonides n. d., undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Yevtushenko with Levins n. d., undated (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Ancel and Reneta Nunn, 1968-2000, 1996-2000 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Yevtushenko at the Airport, Bernardville, NJ, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Yevtushenko Giving Interview[?], undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2. Abroad
    - Abroad, 1960 - 1962; photographs (Box 47, Folder 11)
      USA, 1960; FRG, 1961; Cuba, 1961; Bulgaria, 1961; France, ca. 1962.
    - Abroad, 1963 - 1965; photographs (Box 47, Folder 12)
      Bulgaria, 1964; Italy, 1965.
    - Yugoslavia, 1965; photographs (Box 47, Folder 13)
      with Yugoslav writers; at "Mlodost" in Zagreb.
      Asanovic, Sreten; Perovic, Sreten; Jevtovic, Lala; Sekulovksi, Gojke; Krajevic, Vuk
    - Abroad, 1966; photographs (Box 48, Folder 1)
      Portugal; Beirut; Capri; Libya; New York with Arthur Drexler, Director of Architecture and Design, The Museum of Modern Art.
      Drexler, Arthur; Aitmatov, Chingiz
    - Australia, 1966; photographs (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Melbourne University; Sydney.
      Dutton, Geoffrey; Hardy, Frank; Kongerskaia, Oksana; Meshiakov-Koriakin, Igor; Sofronov, Anatolii
    - Abroad, 1967 - 1969; photographs (Box 48, Folder 3)
      Chile, 1967; Mexico, 1968; Uruguay, 1968; Colombia, 1968.